Daniel Moya

Fullstack Software Engineer

CONTACT INFO

Email: danielmoya.dev@gmail.com | **Linkedin**: linkedin.com/in/daniel-moya Address: Florida, United States

SUMMARY AND OBJECTIVE

I'm a Systems Engineer working as a full stack software engineer with 5 years of in office and remote work experience in the financial, mobility, e-learning, and SaaS industry, employing agile environments to collectively build, improve, and maintain stable software solutions turning legacy applications into modern architectures, while keeping code quality. I'm proficient in web and mobile development (Git, Github, Gitlab), frontend (Html, Css, Javascript, Typescript, React, React Native, Android, iOS), backend (NodeJS, Php, Symphony, Docker), databases (MySQL, MariaDB, Postgresql, MongoDB), testing (Jest, Cypress, Php unit, Codeception, Selenium), DevOps (CircleCi, Github Actions) and cloud solutions (Firebase, GCP, AWS).

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Brightstar Financial - Backend Software Engineer (Contract); USA *Achievements:*

Nov 2023 - Jan 2024

- Implemented SQL, PostgreSQL databases to handle large-scale financial customer data.
- Worked closely with cross-functional teams to deliver timely and accurate software updates.
- Tech Stack: Javascript, Rust, Kotlin, Google Cloud Platform, Amazon Web Service

CuriousInc - Full Stack Software Engineer (Remote); Hengelo (NL)

Aug 2020-Jan 2023

• Project: Dation Dashboard

Achievements:

- Designed migration strategy to cloud and microservices architecture after the company acquired 2 competitors and saved 66% in costs due to duplicate resources.
- o Improved invoices search speed by x5, helping the company maintain the revenue from a big customer.
- Designed and built a recommendation algorithm for lesson appointment scheduling which increases driving school revenue by 20% and customer loyalty by 10%.
- Designed and developed a supercharged agenda for driving schools management adding 10+ new features lacking in the old agenda.
- Increased by 30% market positioning by refactoring 70% outdated UI pages, and features which led to a modern version of the software.
- Tech Stack: HTML 5, Javascript ES23, Typescript 5, Jquery, CSS 3, Bootstrap 5, React 17, Redux Toolkit, Webpack Encore, Jest, Rollbar, Firebase, Unix/Linux, FPM, Cronjobs, Apache Server, Php 8, Symfony 6, Twig, API Platform 3, OOP, ORM, Doctrine, SQL, MariaDB 10, Postgresql 16, Php unit, Codeception, Selenium, CircleCI, Docker compose, GCP, Kubernetes.

Project: Students and Instructors App - Mobile Software Engineer Achievements:

- Created more than 80% of features for the web application.
- Expanded the app with a new module for e-learning with books, video lessons, quizzes, and exams for theory book providers, hence earning 3% revenue per item sold.
- Improved test coverage rates from 60% to 90% in two years, allowing to build and release the apps on Google Play and App Store more frequently and with 60% less bugs.
- Tech Stack: UX, Figma, Javascript ES23, Typescript 5, React 17, React hooks, React Native 0.72, React Test renderer, Snapshot Testing, Gradle 8, Java 10, Ruby 3, Android 13, XCode, CircleCI, Fastlane.

Project: BVO Portal and REST API - Full Stack Software Engineer Achievements:

Built from scratch more than 80% of the main ui features of the web application.

- o Increased the delivery sprint by 35%.
- Reduced bugs per release by 30%, took initiative in adding e2e tests for better quality assurance, testing all core features of the application.
- Helped get 160K EUR with 4 more project phase contracts, after showcasing the main features, tested and within expected timeline in the first phase.
- Tech Stack: HTML 5, Javascript ES23, CSS 3, Bootstrap 5, React 17, React Hooks, Babel, Webpack 5, Jest 29, Cypress 13, Rollbar, Firebase, Unix/Linux, FPM, Cronjobs, Apache Server, Go, Mutex, Functional programming, Doctrine, SQL, MariaDB 10, Postgresql 16, Php unit, Codeception, Selenium, CircleCl, Docker compose, GCP, PubSub.

H.A Systems - Backend Software Engineer (Contract); Caracas (VE) Apr 2020 - Aug 2020 Achievements:

- Implemented code integration, automated testing, staging, versioning and deploying helping improve the team productivity by 30% and complete goals faster.
- Developed ETL pipelines to migrate DB2 database to cloud and improved by 90% the query performance and system reliability.
- Tech Stack:UML, rpg, Python 3, Google Colab, Functional programming, Github Actions, SQL, DB2, IBM I Series, AWS, RDS, CloudWatch.

EMURGO - Frontend Software Engineer (Remote); Tokyo (JP) Aug 2019 - Mar 2020 Achievements:

- Increased by 50% the time to load (TTL) for the content and assets on the website using optimization techniques, boosted the traffic within a 3 months expected timeline.
- Improved the overall SEO Score for the website to 97% reaching better web search positioning.
- Created an e-commerce to strengthen commercial alliances and contribute to the company's brand positioning and revenue increase by 15% selling merchandise products.
- Tech Stack: UX, Figma, HTML 5, Javascript ES17, CSS3, Sass, React 15, MobX, NodeJS 15, Graphql, Babel, Webpack 5, Netlify, Github Actions, Shopify API, Twitter API, Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager, Chrome Lighthouse.

Bicentenario Bank - Software Engineer (Internship); Caracas (VE) **Apr 2019 - Jul 2019** Achievements:

- Reduced by 3 weeks the time to completion of the project quantifying and estimating the total efforts and planning the roadmap for the execution of the credit batch processing project.
- Reduce technical debt within the organization by 25% documenting the system architecture for the credit batch processing project.
- Saved by 70% development and production infrastructure costs by estimating and reserving in advanced storage space and processing capacity required for query execution given a data set.
- Tech Stack: UML, rpg, COBOL, Functional programming, SQL, DB2, IBM I Series.

EDUCATION

• Systems Engineering Bachelor's Degree; University of Margarita, Venezuela Nov 2019

SOFT SKILLS

- Excellent technical and non-technical communication skills.
- Proficient doing research, writing papers and documenting the process and the results.
- Ability to work independently and manage my own schedule.
- Remarkable teammate and contributor.
- 8 years of experience as a teacher in multiple disciplines such as software and music.
- Passion and great ease for teaching others all things related to software engineering within my knowledge and expertise.

COMMUNICATION

• English: Professional written and verbal

• Spanish: Native Speaker

• German: Basic Professional

TOOLS

- IDE & Editors: VSCode, PhpStorm, Webstorm, PyCharm.
- Agile: Jira, Slack, Microsoft Teams, Google Suite.